arbonne.com 2015-02-08

# ARBONNE: Anti-Aging | Skin & Body Care | Cosmetics | Health & Wellness

* * *

Revision Date: 9 SEPTEMBER 2014

We have prepared this Privacy Policy to explain how We collect, use, protect, and disclose information and data when you use www.arbonne.com and any other website or mobile application owned and operated by Us (the “Websites”), and for your purchase and/or use of any Arbonne products or services in the United States. Arbonne International, LLC (“ **Arbonne** ,” “ **We** ,” or “ **Us** ”) provides the Websites.

BY USING THE WEBSITES YOU CONSENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. FROM TIME TO TIME, WE MAY CHANGE THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF WE CHANGE THIS PRIVACY POLICY, WE WILL GIVE YOU NOTICE BY POSTING THE REVISED PRIVACY POLICY ON THE APPLICABLE WEBSITES. THOSE CHANGES WILL GO INTO EFFECT ON THE REVISION DATE SHOWN IN THE REVISED PRIVACY POLICY. BY CONTINUING TO USE THE WEBSITES AFTER THE REVISION DATE, YOU CONSENT TO THE REVISED PRIVACY POLICY.

1.      _Managing Your Information Preferences._

You can always review, correct, or update your Personally Identifiable Information by changing the relevant settings in your Arbonne online account (if available) or by contacting Us by mail, e-mail, or telephone as follows:

Arbonne International, LLC

450 Excel Pkwy, Ste. 600

Addison, Texas 7500

1-888-ARBONNE

Or you may complete the online form at arbonne.com > Contact Us

In addition, you can always opt out of receiving certain e-mails by changing notification settings in your Arbonne online account (if available), clicking the unsubscribe link provided in every email, or by contacting Us by mail, e-mail, or telephone as set forth above. If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact Us by mail, e-mail, or telephone as set forth above.

2.      _Collection and Use of Information._

We may collect Personally Identifiable Information about you (for example, your name, address, telephone number, credit card information, etc.) in order to communicate with you or provide you with products or services that you have requested. “ **Personally Identifiable Information** ” refers to information that you provide to Us through the Internet or otherwise that can be used to uniquely identify you.

Arbonne products are sold through our network of Independent Consultants except that online shopping is fulfilled and sold directly by Arbonne in connection with an Arbonne Independent Consultant. When you register your account online with Arbonne, you will receive an Arbonne identification number (Arbonne ID). Arbonne Independent Consultants, as well as Preferred Clients and Clients who wish to access account information online will also receive a PIN. Please keep your Arbonne ID and PIN secret. You are entirely responsible for any activity under your Arbonne ID. You must promptly notify Arbonne of any actual or attempted unauthorized use of your Arbonne ID.

From time to time, we may establish a business relationship with other businesses that we believe to be trustworthy and who have confirmed that their privacy practices are consistent with ours. We call these businesses our “Approved Partners.” We may also send you e-mail promotions and other information that may be of interest to you from Arbonne or from its Approved Partners.

**We will not sell, transfer or share any Personally Identifiable Information about you to any third parties outside of Arbonne and Arbonne Approved Partners who agree to honor these privacy safeguards, except under circumstances as may be required by law or to protect legal rights. Arbonne Approved Partners may include third party service providers and their independent contractors or affiliates providing products and services as authorized by Arbonne.**

We may collect, use and disclose information that is not Personally Identifiable Information (for example, We may keep track of, use or disclose aggregate statistics regarding the number of visitors to our Websites and other information that does not uniquely identify you). Typically, this data is gathered through the use of automated “cookies,” “Web beacons,” and other similar technologies.

Cookies is a small text file placed on your computer to identify your computer and Internet browser. Web beacons are a file placed on a website that monitors usage. The use of cookies and Web beacons is an industry standard and you will find most major websites use cookies and/or Web beacons. By showing how and when visitors use our Websites on an aggregate basis, cookies and/or Web beacons help Us better determine which areas of our Websites are popular or useful, and which areas are not. Many improvements and updates to our Websites are based on such data as total number of visitors and pages viewed. In addition, We may also solicit your feedback in online surveys that are optional.

We employ some vendors to perform functions on our behalf. Examples may include fulfilling orders, delivering packages, e-mail administrative functions, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These vendors are under a strict contractual obligation to use confidential data only for those purposes for which they are hired.

We may share Personally Identifiable Information and other data with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with Arbonne. If Arbonne is merged, acquired, or sold, or in the event of a transfer of some or all of our assets or equity, we may disclose or transfer Personally Identifiable Information and other data in connection with such transaction. You will have the opportunity to opt out of any such transfer if, in our discretion, the new entity plans to handle your information in a way that differs materially from this Privacy Policy.

3.      _Children._

Our Websites are intended for use by adults and minors over the age of 13. Arbonne does not knowingly collect or use information from minors under the age of 13.

4.      _Privacy Practices of Third Parties and Advertisers._

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any Personally Identifiable Information obtained, held or used in connection with any of Arbonne’s websites located outside of the United States and its territories. Please visit Arbonne’s country specific websites if you require information on the privacy policy applicable to that website.

Our Websites may contain advertisements and links to other websites. Arbonne is not responsible for the content or privacy policies or practices of any advertisers or linked websites or for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third parties. To the extent that you disclose Personally Identifiable Information to any advertisers, linked websites or other third parties, different rules may apply to their use or disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information, and We encourage you to review their privacy policies before disclosing Personally Identifiable Information to them.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our Websites. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g. click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. Our systems do not recognize or respond to browser “Do Not Track” signals, but several of our service providers who utilize these cookies or Web beacons on our Websites enable you to opt out of targeted advertising practices. To learn more about these advertising practices or to opt out of this type of advertising, you can visit www.networkadvertising.org and www.aboutads.info/choices/. We also provide you with additional tools to opt out of marketing from us. You can learn about this in Section 1 above.

5.      _Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement._

Arbonne cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose Personally Identifiable Information and other data to government or law enforcement officials or private parties if, in our discretion, we believe it is necessary or appropriate in order to respond to legal requests (including court orders and subpoenas), to protect the safety, property or rights of Arbonne or of any third party, to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity, or to comply with the law.

6.      _Notice to California Residents/Your California Privacy Rights_

To opt out of sharing your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please contact Us by mail, e-mail, or telephone as follows:

Arbonne International, LLC

450 Excel Pkwy, Ste. 600

Addison, Texas 7500

1-888-ARBONNE

Or you may complete the online form at arbonne.com > Contact Us

You must clearly state your request, including your name, mailing address, e-mail address and phone number. Please see Section 1 (Managing Your Information Preferences) above for additional information.

7.      _Processing in the United States._

Please be aware that your Personally Identifiable Information and other data may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, or country. If you are located outside of the United States, please be advised that we process and store all information in the United States. The laws in the United States may not be as protective of your privacy as those in your location. By using our Websites, you agree that the applicable laws in the United States will govern the collection, use, transfer, and disclosure of your Personally Identifiable Information and other data.

8.      _European Union and Swiss Residents_

If you choose to provide Arbonne with your information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers located in the United States. Arbonne adheres to the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access, and Enforcement, and is registered with the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor Program. Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of your information should be directed to Arbonne by calling us at 0800 977 5721 (in Europe) or 1 800 Arbonne (in the United States) or sending us an email at [privacy@arbonne.com](mailto:privacy@arbonne.com). We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. For complaints that cannot be resolved, we have agreed to participate in the dispute resolution procedures of JAMS pursuant to the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Principles. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Arbonne’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. For clarity, please note that this "European Union and Swiss Residents" section of this Privacy Policy applies only to residents of the European Union and Switzerland.

9.      _Security._

We use technical, physical, and organizational security measures in order to protect the data We have under our control against accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, destruction, or against access by unauthorized persons. Nevertheless, your confidential use of our Websites cannot be guaranteed by us. We shall not be responsible for harm that you or any person may suffer as a result of breach of confidentiality in respect to your use of our Websites or any information you transmit to our Websites.

PLEASE PRINT A COPY OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY FOR YOU RECORDS AND PLEASE CHECK THE WEBSITES FREQUENTLY FOR ANY CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.
